Allan Berry Resume

PO Box 08483 Chicago, IL 60608

(312) 371-8722

allanberry@gmail.com allanberry.com

Profile

I am experienced with digital collections and skilled in the development of systems for their care and maintenance. With a background in technology, education, and the fine and liberal arts, I work hard to make collections more modern, durable and easy to use.

Experience

Berry Catalog Workshop

Principal and Founder: November 2012 – Present

- I build collection systems for private special collections, usually of art and rare books.
- I have catalogued and digitized thousands of rare books, drawings and prints.
- I produce print and digital catalogs, with Python, Processing, InDesign and HTML5.
- I employ contemporary library and software development techniques, with a mind toward open standards, system testing and user experience design.

University of Illinois at Chicago, Learning Sciences Research Institute Software Designer: September 2010 – August 2012

- Designed and produced an integrated set of print books and Java-based software for a high school science education curriculum.
- Managed a Macintosh server and a fleet of laptops.
- Collaborated with a small team, including managing another programmer.
- Regular interaction with users and specialists. Regular user-experience testing.

Roberta Kramer and Associates, Inc., Chicago

Collections Manager: January 2004 – August 2010

- Digitized artworks and developed software for a firm specializing in art collections.
- Clients included Fortune 500 firms, a liberal arts college, and several private collections.

Education

University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign Master of Science (MS): Library and Information Science, 2013

- Concentration in Digital Preservation and Special Collections.
- Completed coursework in Systems, Data Curation, Digital Preservation, Project Management, User Experience Design, and Exhibits.

Art Libraries Society of North America, Summer Educational Institute Certificate: Visual Resources and Image Management, 2012

• Trained in practical physical object digitization, copyright and cataloging procedures.

University of Illinois, Chicago Master of Arts (MA): Art History, 2011

- Concentration in Museum Studies.
- Completed coursework in premodern and modern art, architecture, and art technology.
- Thesis: Documenting the Modern Museum: a Survey of Anglo-American Museum Catalogues.

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA): Painting & Drawing, 1999

• Wilt Memorial Award for drawing.

Internships

The Newberry Library, Special Collections, Cartography

Intern: September 2011 – August 2012

• Assistant cataloger of the Rand McNally map archive, using AACR2 and Library of Congress vocabularies.

University of Illinois at Chicago, Visual Resources Library

Collections Assistant: September 2007 – May 2008

- Researched and digitized images for the university's slide collection.
- Regular use of LUNA, Voyager, and ARTstor.

Technology

I am a proficient full-stack web application developer, with strengths in front-end design and image management.

languages: Python, Java, PHP, JavaScript. I emphasize agile processes, testing, and documentation.

web: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Django, Drupal. I manage web applications from concept to deployment.

data: Microsoft Excel, XML, SQL, Filemaker Pro. I am proficient with domain modeling and large data sets.

design: OmniGraffle, Adobe Illustrator & InDesign. Wireframing and UI/UX are specialties of mine.

visualization: **Processing, D3.** I provide access to abstract data sets in novel and approachable ways.

library: AACR2, MARC, CDWA, VRA-Core, Dublin Core, the OAIS model. I am an efficient, experienced cataloger.

images: Adobe Lightroom & Photoshop. A solid photographer, I employ nondestructive, archival workflows.

Language

- I have excellent command of English, especially with academic writing and documentation.
- I can read German, and I have bibliographic ability with French, Italian, Spanish and Russian.

Selected Publications

The Connected Chemistry Curriculum (Vol. 1-9)

Stieff, M., Nighelli, T., Yip, J., Ryan, S., & Berry, A. (2012). Chicago, IL: University of Illinois at Chicago.

I designed and produced an integrated set of books and Java-based software for the classroom.

Selected Coursework, University of Illinois

- Data Curation (UIUC LIS 590)
- Digital Libraries and Archives (UIUC LIS 590)
- Digital Preservation (UIUC LIS 586)
- Electronic Visualization (UIC AD 406)
- History of Collecting and Museology (UIC AH 480)
- Interfaces to Information Systems (UIUC LIS 590)
- Library and Museum Exhibitions (UIUC LIS 590)
- Museum Informatics (UIUC LIS 490)
- Project Mangagement for Information Science (UIUC LIS 590)
- Systems Analysis and Management (UIUC LIS 453)

Associations

Code4Lib, Art Libraries Society of North America, The Caxton Club.

Interests

I like data visualization, motorcycles, and drawing pictures. I'm also trying to learn guitar; please wish me luck.